[Applause]
he's speaking out he says because
Manulife Bank customers need to know
it's honestly terrifying for almost a
decade he says Manulife Bank of Canada
didn't properly protect millions of
pieces of customer information stored in
a database employees nicknamed data Barn
things like customer names addresses
credit card numbers and social insurance
numbers personal data The Insider says
wasn't properly secured could have ended
up in the wrong hands if taken off site
someone else is reading his words they
could use it to steal your identity they
could open up a line of credit in your
name get credit cards in your name sell
the information to someone else and
there's no way to ever know if it
happened
as concern over data Barnes started to
Bubble Up in 2020 almost a decade after
the database was created the company
began an internal review
it led to this report some key findings
credit card numbers were discovered
unmasked so employees who shouldn't see
all 16 numbers could employees were
sending unencrypted emails containing
customers private information there was
no way to track how data was being
handled customer info was being stored
on laptops when I hear that it is a
large organization an established
organization of that magnitude an
organization that can affect many
Canadians it really is concerning and
shocking quite frankly to hear that this
data Ephesus says big privacy issues in
large corporations like Manulife can
erode customer confidence a company that
has been entrusted with caring for that
information on behalf of Canadians
really should be taking these matters
very very seriously The Insider was part
of a group that sought Solutions but he
says upper management didn't think
fixing databarn was urgent we should not
be waiting for there to be a data breach
before there's action there's a number
of different things that ought to have
been done here and and it doesn't appear
that they have been done according to
the report
spokesperson for Manulife declined our
interview request in a written statement
Manulife said action was taken
immediately after concerns were first
raised to confirm the safety of customer
information and further restrict
internal access the company says the
database meets or exceeds regulatory
requirements for privacy Manulife also
said there was never any evidence
customer information had been misused
the company did not provide a clear
answer when asked how a lack of
information means it can be sure no harm
occurred Erica Johnson CBC News
Vancouver